MRAD EL KHOURY

Al Murooj complexe , Sheikh Zayed Road, Dubai, UAE Contacts: +971 50 6446763 ; E-mail: mrad khoury@yahoo.com

SENIOR PROFILE - HOSPITALITY OPERATIONS



Over 25 years' international experience in sales, marketing business development, cluster operations and multiple property management in 5 star hospitality business at corporate level mainly across **Middle East, Europe.** Articulate and strategy-driven professional with strong business acumen, quality & customer focus and ability to manage operations to execute business plan in consistent with strategic intent of business while consistently achieving business goals and ensuring revenue growth and best-in-class customer experience. Genuine desire to excel in all facets of operations with unrelenting commitment to customer service translating into all-time high customer satisfaction and brand acceptance.

Areas of Expertise

- Strategic Business Planning
- Business Plan Execution
- Budgets/ Financial Planning
- CAPEX /OPEX Administration
- Strong Sales & marketing background
- · Hotels & Resorts Management
- Policy & Procedures Admin
- Operations Management
- Pre-opening experience
- Revenue/P&L Management
- Business Process Improvement
- Projects & Facilities Mgmt.
- · Performance Management

- Relationships Management
- Team Building and Leadership.
- Launch Campaigns and Events Management.
- F&B Concept development and Execution.

EXECUTIVE SYNOPSIS

- Broad based experience in new hotel opening and entire operations of hospitality business within the frame work of corporate excellence programs aligned with visions, missions and business strategy of the company.
- Deft at setting operating strategy and plan, performance standards, process & procedures best suited for the transition of business plan, underpinning highest standards of services quality, productivity, efficiency, sales, and customer satisfaction.
- Extensive experience in sales & marketing, financial planning & budgeting, resources management, expenses control, yield & productivity improvement, project management, customer service, and stakeholders' relationships management.
- Proven ability to strategize and administer hospitality management functions in terms of revenue forecasting & budgeting,
 sales & marketing, F&B operations, value creation in services, guest experience management, and improvement of service level.
- Proven ability to strategize & administer hospitality property management functions in terms of assets maintenance, advanced featuring of product, property refurbishment, facilities management, security & housekeeping, etc.
- Leadership experience in property development projects management with overall administration of budgets and contracts, technical deliveries, coordination with project players, supervision of construction, quality control, and close out functions.
- Influencing & decisive leader with executive leadership skills; strong communication, interpersonal and problem solving skills; empathetic with emotional intelligence; champion people development through coaching/mentoring/ training; and manage cross-functional team performance through empowerment and competency building.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Cluster General Manager

Jan 2020 - FeB 2021

Key Highlights

- Oversaw cluster operations encompassing 2 five star city hotels.(Swissotel AL Murooj & Movenpick Grand Al Bustan)
- Clustered the main departments which improved efficiency and productivety and reduced cost of operation.(During Covid period)
- Managed the staff redundancies during the COVID lock down period.
- Monitored & coordinated the new rebranding and systems connectivity of both hotels.
- Significantly contributed in revenue generation during covid period by securing groups during the lock down.
- Improved corporate contracting and business mix shift, based on new local market conditions.
- Monitored expenses and significantly reduced cost in both hotels.
- Lead and guide multi-tier team in conduct of day to day business including customer service.
- Proactively liaise with authorities to meet DTCM and DHA COVID safety best practices to secure guests and staff.
- Implemented the company policies and procedures with the cluster HOD's.
- Working closely with HOD's to improve guest's satisfaction and improve hotel ranking.
- Lead the team to improve service quality as per company guidelines.
- Worked closely with the marketing team on CSR activities
- Increase social Media market visibility for both hotels.

Property Description

- Grand Millennium Business Bay (opening) 251 rooms and 2 outlets / Ballroom and 11 Meeting rooms.
- Grand Millennium Dubai Al Barsha Area 334 rooms, 5 restaurants and bars / medium ballroom and 4 meeting rooms.

Job Profile

- Set strategic goals, objectives, budgets, policies, and procedures to enhance revenue, market share and profitability.
- Provide advice, guidance and direction to the departmental managers in implementing business plan and strategies.
- Review team performances and operating results on a regular basis, analyze gaps, and initiate corrective actions to ensure that company's short term and long term objectives are met.
- Promote the company's direction & momentum, business performance, the positive external impact (image), internal business climate, people and services.
- Assist in the preparation of the financial budgets and monitor financial performance versus the budget.
- Lead and guide multi-tier team in conduct of day to day business including customer service
- Proactively liaise with authorities and formulate strategies for business development and maximize revenue generation.
- Establish healthy business relations for securing repeat business and sustainable customer loyalty.
- Lead & gear up performance of management team to consistently deliver results and enhance customer experience.
- Suggest management reviews on strategies on new challenges including remedial action where necessary.
- Develop and maintain high level contacts with local authorities, customers and the external business environment in order to promote company objectives as they relate to operations.
- Monitor & endorse the Operations annual business plans and ensure adequate allocation of staff & resources to meet targets.
- Identify, recommend and approve continuous improvement programs to improve and/or sustain all round performance levels.
- Ensure standards and procedures are established in each department and area of business to ensure objectives are met.
- Evaluate the performance & maintenance cost of assets, while establishing asset management strategy & roadmap.
- Develop and monitor KPIs and ensures KPI targets and results are communicated to all staff effectively.
- Ensure guidance and counselling is available to staff, with a clear objective of career development.
- Set a provision of formal and informal feedback, appraisal and succession planning for subordinate staff.

Key Highlights

- Increased productivty and reduced cost for main departments due to the cluster set up.
- Centralised purchasing to secure best value of procuement budget.
- Reduced PTER of both hotels, and increased hotels revenue and ADR.
- Increased guest satisfaction by 13%.
- Increased ADR by 12%
- Gained Market share and positioned the hotels from 5th to 3rd position on STR
- Converted financial figures from LOP to GOP

General Manager, Crown Plaza Hotel - Sheikh Zayed Road, Dubai

Apr 2018 - Oct 2018

Key Highlights

- Improved staff turnover and productvity by restructuring departments and developing people.
- Boosted outlets revenue and banquet revenue by increasing sale and improving service standard.
- Elevated ranking of the hotel by 2 spots (from 5th to 3rd) on STR.
- Reduced PTER by around 15%, and GOP by 2.5%.
- Implemented renovation of the hotel closely working with consultant and constructors.

(change of management took place, when the hotel management contract was converted into franchise)

Area General Manager, Nassima Hotels (Acico Group) - UAE & Kuwait

Jun 2017 - Apr 2018

Key Highlights

- Oversaw operations of 4 hotels & Resorts across UAE and Kuwait.
 - Nassima Hotel (Voco) Sheikh Zayed Dubai
 - Nassima Suites Furnished apartments
 - Radisson Hotel & Resort Fujairah
 - Palm Hotel & Resort Kuwait
- Restructured hotels operations, established operation standards and implemented centralized purchasing.
- Developed new F&B concepts and opened new outlets.
- Increased F&B revenue by more than 20%.
- Improved GOP by 7% and reduced PTER by almost 5%.

Growth Path

• Oct'03 – Feb'06 Area Director of Sales & Marketing, Dubai & Northern Emirates

Mar'06 – Dec'08 General Manager, Burjuman Rotana Suites
 Jan'09 – Apr'11 General Manager Fujairah Rotana Resort & Spa

Mar'11 – Sep'15 General Manager, Towers Rotana Hotel
 Aug'15 – Jun'17 Cluster GM, Dubai & Northern Emirates

- Cove Rotana Resort & SPA and Cove Rotana All Inclusive Resort.
- Fujairah Rotana Resort & SPA
- Arjan Fujairah Hotel

Key Highlights

- Oversaw cluster operations encompassing 2 five star resorts and one city hotel.
- Received Chairman Award for best performing area and best performing GM, 2017.
- Opened the Cove Rotana hotel extention of 148 rooms.
- Significantly contributed in renovation of new outlets and opening of 148 units.
- Improved hotels market share and STR rank from 4th to 2nd in occupancy and 3rd on REVPAR.
- Improved GOP by 5%, while reducing overall cost by around 7%.
- Clustered the main departments which improved efficiency and productivety and reduced cost of operation.
- Reduced staff turnover by 7%.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Opening Director of Sales & Marketing, Le Royal Hotel - Beirut, Lebanon	Mar 2003 - Oct 2003
Acting Area Director of Sales & Marketing, Pre-opening Sheraton Coral Beach Hotel & Resort - Beirut	
Jan 2002 - Feb 2003	1000 0000
Director of Sales & Marketing, Sheraton Riyadh Hotel & Towers – Riyadh, KSA	1999 - 2002
Director of Sales & Marketing, Sheraton Deira Hotel & Towers - Dubai, UAE	1999
Pre-opening Team Member, Le Bristol-Luxury Collection (Sheraton) - Beirut, Lebanon	1998 - 1999
Managing Director Market Key Agency - Beirut, Lebanon (Marketing, Events& Exhibitions)	1996 - 1998
Area Director Sales & Marketing (ME), Abbar & Zeiny Group - Jeddah, KSA	1993 - 1996
Operations Manager , Market Key Agency - Beirut, Lebanon	1987 - 1993

CREDENTIALS

Education

- One year Master degree in International Affairs & Diplomacy, NDU Lebanon, 1999.
- Bachelor of Science degree in Marketing & Management, Notre Dame University (NDU), Lebanon.

Professional Development

- Hospitality Project Development & Innovation Lausanne.
- Area sales trainer –Starwood Hotels& Resorts
- Senior management training Rotana Hotels
- Management development training
- Zodiac training Senior management course
- Service for excellency training
- Train the trainer

Computer Literacy

• MS Office, MS Project, Fidelio & Opera.

PERSONAL PARTICULARS

- Languages Known: Fluent English, French, and Arabic.
- Nationality: Holding dual Nationality: Lebanese/Dominica.
- Holder Canadian PR
- Passport Status: No. RL 4032982, valid till 2024.
- Visa Status: Residence visa.
- Marital Status: Married